

## **PERSONAL BRIEF**

- SALES &MARKETINGPROFESSIONAL
- 9 YEARS OF
   EXPERIENCE
- PLAYED BOTH HQ &FIELD ROLESUCCESSFULLY
- ASPIRING BUSINESS
   LEADER

# **SKILLS**

MS EXCEL	00000
POWER POINT	00000
AREA MANAGEMENT BUSINESS	0000
MANAGEMENT & PLANNING	0000
TALENT REVIEW	00000
GOALS & PERFORMANCE	0000
BUSINESS IDEAS	00000
VENDOR MANAGEMENT	00000

## **LANGUAGES**

# MD. IMTIAZ ALAM



Bashundhara, Dhaka

iasohan@hotmail.com



+88 01672076903

https://www.linkedin.com/in/iasohan/

# **CAREER SUMMARY**

As a Sales & Marketing professional I have substantial experience in trade marketing, distribution and consumer activation. Played the role of Executive, Trade Marketing in JTI designing trade programs & monitoring merchandising distribution & execution. Also worked as Merchandising Manager as National Lead & introduced multiple value added merchandising for national launch. In addition, as Area Field Marketing Manager lead a team who have the expertise on preparing consumer engagement, trade engagement & activation programs along with maintaining budgets. Currently as Area Sales Manager, managing the distributors & depot houses by ensuring primary and as well as ensuring secondary through sales & distribution (Strike rate, LPC & brand productivity ratio) in the market.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **AREA MANAGER, SALES OPERATIONS (SEP 2021 to Till date)**

#### JAPAN TOBACCO INTERNATIONAL

- Sales & Trade Strategy with New product launching planning & execution
- Distributor Management
- Internal & External Customer Relation
- Inventory Management
- Sales Information Management
- Drive a winning team culture through Training & Development as well as manage the talent and develop them for the next level as well as contribute to business
- Monitoring the program for excellent execution
- Evaluate the program for understanding the program success & also prepare closure report

#### SPECIAL PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Consecutive growth in ADS for last 4 months (5% growth vs Jan'21)
- Successfully ensure 96% Distribution of New Product (Navy Option) where target was 80%

#### AREA MANAGER, FIELD MARKETING (Dec 2019 to Aug 2021)

#### JAPAN TOBACCO INTERNATIONAL

- Drive a winning team culture by prioritizing training and development of Field Marketing Team.
- Consult, identify and confirm with Field Marketing team members (Consumer Planning and Activation) the adult smoker profiles of each brand.
- Develops a framework for the Area on how to identify and win the adult smoker at different touch points of the trade or places of interest
- Review & classify outlets according to its channel segmentation and its role and able to support Field Marketing team in the communication and activation of these channels.
- Align and work with sales operations in endorsing channel activations revolving around the target consumer
   & ensure optimum allocation of resources that support the agreed field marketing strategies.
- Plan and complete field marketing campaigns after conducting preliminary research and briefing the Field force
- Monitoring the program for excellent execution. Evaluate the program for understanding the program success & also prepare closure report

#### **SPECIAL PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Achieve 105% consumer contact vs target at NAVY CENTURY Campaign on 2021
- 90% accuracy at consumer contact through proper training, execution and monitoring on 2021

### **EDUCATION**

MBA Eastern University 2013 - 2014

**BBA** 

Eastern University 2007 - 2012

HSC Dhaka Board 2005 - 2007

SSC Dhaka Board 2005

## **INTEREST**

TRAVELLING

GAME

MUSIC

TEA

#### MERCHANDISING MANAGER, NATIONAL LEAD (MAR 2019 to NOV 2019)

#### JAPAN TOBACCO INTERNATIONAL

- Planning & developing merchandising strategy
- Developing New POSM as well as Create mockup for POSM
- Take approval from other department and maintain alignment
- Create timeline for POSM production & delivery
- Develop execution plan & guideline for field force
- Supervise operations and monitor progress of project
- Create report for line Manager & top management
- Follow up team member for POSM distribution & reporting
- Collect report from team member & share it with concern department

#### **SPECIAL PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Successfully introduced & launched customized Rickshaw Van (Tri Van) in Bangladesh Market with completely new look & usability to ensure JTI visibility in the market and as well as to develop the brand value
- Successfully launch SHEIKH REJUVENATION POSM within the given timeline March 2019 & LD POSM in 2 (two) phases during the new brand LD launch

#### **TRADE MARKETING EXECUTIVE (APR 2017 to FEB 2019)**

#### JAPAN TOBACCO INTERNATIONAL

- Leading Market Developer project nationally
- Develop Process for working module of Market Developer
- Trade Loyalty program lead
- Trade Program design & execution lead
- Preparing the national cycle plan for Winston brand
- Merchandising lead national for Winston Brand

#### SPECIAL PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Successfully Launch "APON RETAILER" program which was basically a Retail Loyalty Program for Winston brand
- Contributed 22% incremental volume through APON RETAILER

#### FIELD OPERATION OFFICER (JAN 2016 to MAR 2017)

#### JAPAN TOBACCO INTERNATIONAL

- Supervise the sales team and execute daily sales activities to ensure sales target achievement
- Maintaining trade relations with business partners
- Implement corporate planning and policies in the market in line with sales forecast team

#### JUNIOR OFFICER (FEB 2013 to DEC 2015)

#### Fareast Islami Life Insurance Co. Ltd

- Worked for Branch control department
- Find places for branch offices
- Renew the office rental contract & negotiate with landlords

## REFERENCES

# **MD ZAHIR RAIHAN**

REGIONAL MANAGER
JAPAN TOBACCO INTERNATIONAL
+88 01819210263

MdZahir.Raihan@iti.com

# **HELAL KHAN**

SENIOR GENERAL MANAGER CHANNEL i +88 01713010674